frostclick.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy Policy - FrostWire - BitTorrent Client, Cloud Downloader, Media Player. 100% Free Download, No subscriptions required.

##### **1.0 What personally identifiable information does FrostWire collect from me, when and why?**

FrostWire endeavors to collect as little personally identifiable information as possible. The FrostWire Software and the sections of the FrostWire Websites that do not require a log in do not collect any personally identifiable information, however, the use of the FrostWire online forum (forum.frostwire.com) an the support pages (support.frostwire.com) requires a disclosure of some personal information.

##### **1.1 FrostWire Online Forum (forum.frostwire.com)**

FrostWire does not collect any personally identifiable information while you browse the forum, but if you would like to post to the forum, you need to register. During registration, FrostWire asks for your email address, whether you have attained the age of thirteen years, and other communication methods which you may provide at your election. This information is only used to identify you as a contributor to the forum, allow you to get notifications on the forum’s activity that is relevant to you and for the forum administrators to contact you if needed.

You may edit your FrostWire Forum Information at any time by using your FrostWire ID and password.

##### **1.2 FrostWire Support Page (support.frostwire.com)**

FrostWire does not collect any personally identifiable information while you browse the support articles. Nonetheless, the support section is administered by a third party, which might collect some analytical data and will ask for your email address and name if you will want to submit a support request. That information is available to us to view and edit, but is stored at the third party service’s servers. This information is only used to provide you with the requested customer service. Zendesk is the current support pages technology provider. 

You may edit your FrostWire Support Information at any time by logging into your account. If you would like to delete your account, please submit a support ticket using the account you would like deleted.

##### **1.3 Our Blog (https://frostwire.wordpress.com/)**

FrostWire does not collect any personally identifiable information while you browse the articles on the blog, nonetheless the blog itself is hosted on Wordpress servers and Wordpress can collect some personal data in accordance with their Privacy Policy. Wordpress is an Automatic Project and you can find their privacy policy here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>

Should you choose to add a comment to any post that we have published on our blog, the name and email address you enter with your comment will be saved to Wordpress’ database, along with your computer’s IP address and the time and date that you submitted the comment. This information is only used to identify you as a contributor to the comment section of the specific blog post. Only your name will be shown on the public-facing website although if the supplied email address is linked to a Gravatar account, your [Gravatar](http://en.gravatar.com/) photo will also be displayed.

Your comment and the personal data associated with it will remain on published until we remove the comment or the entire blog post. Should you wish to have the comment and it’s associated personal data deleted, please [email us here](mailto:support@frostwire.com?subject=Blog%20post%20comment%20removal) using the email address that you commented with.

##### **1.6 Frostclick.com (http://www.FrostClick.com)**

FrostWire does not collect any personally identifiable information while you browse the articles on FrostClick.com. The website uses Google Analytics to obtain analytical data and AdSense advertising service by Google to display ads.

##### **1.7 Contact Forms and Email Links**

Should you choose to contact us using the contact form on our Give page or email us directly from your email client, none of the data that you supply will be stored by our website. Instead the data will be collated into an email and sent to us over the Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP) to G-Suite email servers on Google Cloud. You can find more information about Google Cloud’s Privacy Policy here: <https://support.google.com/googlecloud/answer/6056650?hl=en>

We would suggest that you always consider email as an insecure medium and not include personal, confidential or otherwise sensitive information within an email.

##### **1.8 Email newsletter**

If you choose to join our email newsletter, the email address that you submit to us will be forwarded to [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/) who is our email marketing service provider. The email address that you submit will not be stored within this website’s own database or in any of our internal computer systems.

Your email address will remain within MailChimp’s database for as long as we continue to use MailChimp’s services for email marketing or until you specifically request removal from the list. You can do this by unsubscribing using the unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send you or by [requesting removal via email](mailto:support@frostwire.com?subject=Website%20newsletter%20unsubscribe). When requesting removal via email, please send your email to us using the email account that is subscribed to the mailing list.

You can view MailChimp’s Privacy Policy here: <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

##### **1.9 The FrostWire Software and Anonymous Usage Statistics**

The FrostWire software does not collect any data about its users that can personally identify them. Nonetheless, FrostWire collects Anonymous Usage Statistics.

FrostWire has an opt-out configuration option to collect and send anonymous user interface usage data. When selected during the configuration wizard screen or through the application settings it allows users to automatically upload completely anonymous user experience statistics. The data collected does not contain any personally identifiable information, nor any information regarding searches made, content downloaded or content consumed.

This information is not and will not be shared with third parties and it is intended to measure how effective the FrostWire user interface features are. You can see exactly all the user interface events being collected in [our source code](https://github.com/frostwire/frostwire/blob/master/common/src/main/java/com/frostwire/uxstats/UXAction.java) which is absolutely open and free to all.

To prevent FrostWire from collecting the Anonymous Usage Statistics in your desktop client, go to Preferences > Advanced > Usage Statistics and unblock the checkbox nest to ‘Send anonymous usage statistics’. If you are using FrostWire’s Android client, go to the apps Settings > Notification and Other and tap on the Anonymous Usage Statistics box to deselect the option.

##### **2.0 Site visitation tracking and cookies**

Like most websites, FrostWire Websites use Google Analytics (GA) to track user interaction. The data is used to determine the number of people using FrostWire Websites, to better understand how they find and use those web pages and to see their journey through each website.

Although GA records data such as your geographical location, device, internet browser and operating system, none of this information personally identifies you to FrostWire. GA also records your computer’s IP address, which could be used to personally identify you, but Google does not allow FrostWire access to this data.

GA makes use of cookies, details of which can be found on [Google’s developer guides.](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage)

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. All FrostWire webpages where you are prompted to login or that are customizable require that you accept cookies.

Generally, we use cookies to streamline your experience with the website through use of the forum and support pages. This cookie is set when you register or "Sign In" and is modified when you "Sign Out" of our services.

FrostWire does not track or monitor audience size and forum usage.

Disabling cookies on your internet browser will stop GA and FrostWire from tracking any part of your visit to pages within this website.

##### **2.1 Ads, third party links and co-brand relationships**

In an attempt to provide increased value to our visitors, FrostWire may choose various third party web sites or services to link to, and/or frame within, the FrostWire Websites or Software. FrostWire may use [third-party advertising companies](http://d2jp8u3ajngjmj.cloudfront.net/pp.html) to serve ads when you visit the FrostWire Websites or use the FrostWire Software. FrostWire may also include offers from third parties as part of the installation process of its software. FrostWire also participates in co-branding, affiliate marketing and other relationships to offer e-commerce and other services and features to our users. FrostWire has no control over these third party sites or services, each of which has separate privacy and independent data collection practices. FrostWire has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or actions, and is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any such websites or services.

**Special Adsense Notification**

In this usage policy, the Adsense usage disclaimer has been added by the recommendation of Google, which serves ads on frostwire.com and frostclick.com through its Adsense program.

When you visit www.frostwire.com and www.frostclick.com and click an advertisement syndicated by Google, a cookie (< a href="https://www.doubleclickbygoogle.com/" target="_blank">DoubleClick DART Cookie) is automatically added to your browser to help Google deliver you more targeted and useful ads.

If you do not wish to get the cookie on your browser, you can visit Google ad and content network privacy policy.

This is done in accordance with the [Google Adsense policies](https://support.google.com/adsense/topic/1261918?visit_id=1-636620980137030980-340397234&ctx=as2&rd=2), [Google Adsense terms and conditions](https://www.google.com/adsense/new/localized-terms?gsessionid=QrNAnsq9JeWex0FC_uVBMloCV_vBjzQC), and the latest notification of changes in Google's [official Inside Adsense blog here](https://adsense.googleblog.com/2008/02/updated-terms-and-conditions.html).

##### **3.0 How the FrostWire Client Works**

The FrostWire Client is a software application that runs directly on your machine (a desktop computer or a mobile device) that manages downloads. The FrostWire Client downloads files by trading pieces with other users on the BitTorrent network that are downloading or have downloaded the same files before. When you download or select to seed your downloaded files, other users will upload file pieces from you. Even though your IP address is associated with your file chunks and that information will be available to other users on the network, other users will not have any other information about you.

FrostWire does not track the files you transfer over the BitTorrent network.

##### **4.0 Data sharing with third parties**

As a general rule, FrostWire will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under court order or subpoena.

FrostWire may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating FrostWire's Terms and Conditions of Use or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) FrostWire's rights or property, other FrostWire users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. FrostWire may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.

##### **5.0 About Children’s Online Privacy Protection**

FrostWire’s Websites and Services are openly available to a general audience. Children should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to anyone online. FrostWire does not share personal information about users under the age of 16 with third parties and we do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of age. In addition, FrostWire will not send any direct email offers to users who indicate they are under the age of 16.

##### **6.0 Questions? Contact us.**

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to contact at frostwire dot com.

##### **7.0 Notification of changes**

Please be aware that by visiting the FrostWire Websites or Services you consent to the collection and use of information by FrostWire as set forth in this privacy policy. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes within this page so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

##### **8.0 Terms and Conditions**

Please make sure to familiarize yourself with the [Terms of Service](http://www.frostwire.com/terms) and the [End User License Agreement](http://www.frostwire.com/eula) establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of the FrostWire Websites and Services.

Please be aware that FrostWire does not solicit or anticipate use of this site by any individuals or entities outside of the jurisdiction of the United States.
